<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Serradas.org - 2020-review</title><link href="https://serradas.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://serradas.org/feeds/2020-review.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://serradas.org/</id><updated>2021-01-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>2020 Review</title><link href="https://serradas.org/2020-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-01-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ruben Serradas</name></author><id>tag:serradas.org,2021-01-05:/2020-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wow last year was crap! But it forced every one of us to reflect better on our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can divide what I got from last year in two:
1. On writing ideas.
2. On a personal level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first part of the year I made Rocket Launcher and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wow last year was crap! But it forced every one of us to reflect better on our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can divide what I got from last year in two:
1. On writing ideas.
2. On a personal level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first part of the year I made Rocket Launcher and SecondBrainio. This is what I've learned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No one really cares.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Failure doesn't exist outside your mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more personal note, from the second part of the year I got this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing nothing sometimes is the best thing to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People have problems too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't be so though with yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're here reading this, it could look rough. But I'll clarify every point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On Working in Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;No One Really Cares&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've always read that no one cares for your side projects online, in books and videos but I never understood
the extent to which people didn't care for what you do. You can see this as a barrier but in reality this is a great
potential to do things the way you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write it the best I can. If you're trying something new, maybe a project to which you've put a lot of dedication and heart: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NO ONE CARES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could transfer my knowledge and put it in your brain I would so you wouldn't have to go through a process of doubting yourself
and fearing failure. Everyone &lt;em&gt;fails&lt;/em&gt; (I'll write about this in the next section) at some point of another. Furthermore, you're going to die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why don't just do it anyways? The best you can and how you feel should be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Failure doesn't exist outside your mind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a corollary from &lt;strong&gt;No one really cares&lt;/strong&gt;, nothing awful happens if you stop working on a project, unless you've already invested
a lot of money on something. 
Being a coward and doubting yourself just stops you from having fun. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fear of shame and failure is just a feeling at the end of the day. Yes, you'll feel bad. But are you going to let your feelings dictate
how you're going to live? I know I won't. Stand up and keep trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Have fun&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sit in front of the computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sip some coffee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is it. Don't expect a great breakthrough. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like a simple thing. But I've forgotten to have fun for a long time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're reading this, don't forget to have fun. Your well-being matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Personal Side&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write this as a reminder to myself and to help others. 
Normally I wouldn't write anything personal here but these are nice 
understanding on their own and if I don't write them, it would be an incomplete review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Doing nothing sometimes is the best thing to do&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm serious. Taking time to reflect and being with yourself is really important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I evaded many events from my life until I had a chance to face them. 
At the end this helped me have a bigger clarity and peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand when your day is not full of things to do and responsibilities you have
the chance to let your imagination act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also applies on several things in life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.investmentnews.com/sometimes-best-strategy-is-to-do-nothing-51404"&gt;Sometimes the best strategy is to do nothing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thetaoteching.com/"&gt;Tao Te Ching&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a parenthesis, doing nothing is really hard. If you can't follow or you think this idea is stupid I can totally get you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;People have problems too&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I forgot sometime that other people have problem in their lives. It's not like 
I wasn't aware of it. It was more like ignoring the fact and overlooking them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes, they have problems, but they're not as big as MY problems.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is crazy. But it took me a global pandemic to understand that everyone has problems, and they're important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what's with that? I want to shift myself and my goals towards a more humane way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll expand on that in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Don't be so thought on yourself&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Things take time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a reminder for me and for every lovely person who reads this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was my 2020 in review. It might look strange but I'm pretty happy with last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you could get something from this blog post. If you want to talk, write me an email to ruben at serradas dot org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a great day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020-review"></category><category term="review"></category></entry></feed>